

## **Alex Pliutau, Engineering Lead**

Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience bringing products from concept to release in a variety of environments and companies. Organizational and leadership skills garnered from multiple supervisory positions, including but not limited to: mentoring, appropriate delegation, flat organizational communication, task assignment & assistance. Love challenges, clean code, concise documentation, clear communication and constructive feedback. My biggest strengths are APIs, Containers, Cloud, Web, Microservices. Currently I like to use Go to build scalable and fault tolerant backend systems.

Links

<u>Stackoverflow</u>

**Youtube** 

<u>Github</u>

Linkedin

Blog

**Employment History** 

#### **Engineering Lead at Solsten, Berlin**

January 2019 — Present

- Architected a Cloud-native backend for a company product from scratch using Microservices, Go, Kubernetes
- Manage, coach, and lead a team of 10+ engineers, including reviewing their performance and goals and providing ongoing professional development
- · Contributing to interviewing, hiring, and training new engineers
- Led the information security certification process for ISO27001, automated security best practices in Cloud

#### **Engineering Manager at Wizeline, Ho Chi Minh City**

May 2018 — September 2018

- Managed 10 engineers
- Delivered process improvements across the engineering department
- Connected with clients by presenting and explaining software architecture proposals
- Performed > 100 technical interviews
- Improved the interview process, by preparing new on-site challenges
- Running internal training programs

#### Senior Software Engineer at Wizeline, Ho Chi Minh City

March 2017 — May 2018

Lead a team of engineers to build Facebook Messenger Bot, using Node.js for API

- · Built a project utilizing Wit.ai for NLU
- Built Google Home Voice Bot with AWS Lambda and Serverless
- Built a facial recognition office assistant using Go and Tensorflow
- Held few internal and public tech talks: Microservices with Go, The Art of Git.

#### Senior Software Engineer at Lazada, Ho Chi Minh City

October 2014 — March 2017

- Lead software development subteam in DevOps team
- Helped the company to migrate a monolith to microservices on Kubernetes
- Created a web and CLI project to create a new microservice based on a standard template, which automated the deployment, service registry and configuration
- Developed a company-wide data migration tool in Go based on golang-migrate open source project
- Technologies used: Golang, Javascript, Docker, Kubernetes, Beanstalkd, Jenkins, MySQL

#### Senior Fullstack Engineer at Tuffle, Minsk

November 2012 — September 2014

- Lead a team of 6 engineers to build a tech stack for a social network platform
- Selected appropriate libraries and open source technologies for project integration
- Deployed the solution to bare-metal servers using Ansible
- Technologies used: PHP, Javascript, MySQL, MongoDB, Memcached, Nginx

### Software Engineer at iTechArt, Minsk

August 2010 — October 2012

- I was working in the Backend team providing services for clients
- At that time I mostly used PHP and it's frameworks such as Zend Framework
- Was working on security optimizations for web projects, protecting the system from SQL injections, CSRF, XSS

#### Education

# Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics, Minsk

January 2007 — January 2012

Skills

Cloud-native applications

**APIs** 

**gRPC** 

Web development

Infrastructure as Code

CI/CD

**Google Cloud** 

**AWS** 

**Kubernetes** 

Microservices

Go

**Python** 

**Typescript** 

**Javascript** 

**System Design** 

**Project Management** 

**Training and Mentoring**